J. Robert Oppenheimer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Membership File, 1943-1967 (Box 110-153)
  - American Physical Society
    - Bulletin-Physical Review separation, 1949
    - Coffin-Swope Fellowship Committee, 1948
    - Committee appointments by Oppenheimer, 1948-1949
    - Council
      - Agenda, 1948-1952
      - Arrangements for meetings, 1948-1955
      - Committee on Foreign Relations, 1949
      - Committee on Long-Range Planning, 1954
      - Committee on Science Abstracts, 1945-1950
      - Memoranda, 1947-1966
      - Minutes of the meetings, 1947-1951
      - Statements, Undated
    - Darrow, Karl, correspondence, 1945-1961 (Box 114)
    - General correspondence, 1947-1961
    - General information, 1949-1951
    - Journals, distribution of, 1948-1949
    - Laue, Max von, request for material, 1948-1949
    - Marcellus Hartley Award, 1951
    - Meetings
      - Announcements, 1949-1966
      - Arrangements, 1947-1951
      - Programs, 1953-1957
    - National Science Fund, 1948
    - Nominating Committee, 1949-1958
    - Reports, 1947-1957
    - Semi-Centennial Committee, 1947
    - Travel to meetings, 1947
  - Amnesty International, 1963
  - AMVETS National Service Foundation, 1952-1953
  - Annals of Physics, 1956-1965
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1963
  - Association of Los Alamos Scientists, 1945-1946 (Box 115)
  - Association of Pasadena Scientists, 1945-1946
  - Association of Scientists for Atomic Education, 1946-1947
  - Association of Scientists for Atomic Information, 1947
  - Association of Scientists of Cornell University, 1946
  - Atlantic Union Committee, 1959-1965
  - Atomic Scientists of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1946
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists
    - Article request, 1956
    - Bylaws, 1949-1965
    - Correspondence
      - Amrine, Michael, 1952
      - Davies, T. Harrison, 1950-1952
      - Golden, William T., 1952
      - Rabinowitch, Eugene, 1952-1963
      - Rubinow, Raymond S., 1949
      - Simpson, John, 1947-1955
    - Dinner 1950
    - Emergency Committee mailing, 1949
    - Foundations (Box 116)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1952
      - Ford Foundation, 1951-1953
      - Hofheimer Foundation, 1949-1952
    - Fund-raising, 1952, 1963, (2 folders)
    - General correspondence, 1947-1966, (2 folders)
    - Goldsmith Memorial Lecture, 1950-1951
    - Miscellaneous, 1949-1962
    - Oram and Rich program, 1949 (Box 117)
    - Reprints of articles, 1952-1960
    - Sponsoring Committee, 1948-1954, (3 folders)
    - Subscriptions, 1947-1951
  - “C” miscellaneous, 1962-1966
  - Cabot (Hugh) Memorial Fund, 1946
  - Cambridge Philosophical Society, Undated
  - Case Institute of Technology, Cleveland, Ohio, 1952-1955
  - Century Association, 1967
  - Chaim Weizmann World Memorial Committee See Container 153, Wiezmann (Chaim) World Memorial Committee
  - Christ's College Club, Christ's College, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, England, 1965-1966
  - Comité d'Honneur for the Fondation Einstein, 1956 (Box 118)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1953
  - Committee for Foreign Correspondence, 1948
  - Committee on Science and Freedom, 1954-1965, (2 folders)
  - Committee on the Present Danger
    - General correspondence, 1951-1952
    - Minutes 1951
    - Objectives, 1951
    - Oppenheimer appointment as member, 1951
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion
    - Finkelstein, Louis, correspondence, 1948-1966
    - General, 1951-1966
    - Mohonk Lake Conference, Mohonk, N.Y., 1950-1951
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1960-1967 (Box 119)
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - American-Soviet relations study group, correspondence
      - McCloy, John Jay, 1953-1955
      - Roberts, Henry L., 1953
    - Correspondence, 1945-1966, (2 folders)
    - Discussion group, science and the national interest, 1965-1967, (3 folders)
    - Nuclear weapons foreign policy study group, 1955
  - Davis, Elmer, memorial to, 1958 (Box 120)
  - Denison University, Granville, Ohio, convocation, 1949
  - Disarmament and Arms Control, 1961-1966, (2 folders)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial Foundation See Container 144, Roosevelt (Eleanor) Memorial Foundation
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1943-1963
  - Federation of American Scientists
    - Administrative Committee, 1947-1955
    - Atomic Energy Commission controversy, 1949-1954
    - Ballots, 1950-1954
    - Committee for Foreign Correspondence, 1946-1947
    - Correspondence, 1943-1947, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1962
  - Fieldston School, New York, N.Y., 1950-1954 (Box 121)
  - Freedom House, 1955
  - Gazette Apicole, 1965
  - Goethean Literary Society, 1947
  - Harvard College Board of Overseers, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 122)
    - Adams House, 1951-1952
    - Arts and Sciences Visiting Committee, 1951-1955
    - Bundy, McGeorge, correspondence, 1955
    - Chemistry Department Visiting Committee, 1949-1954
    - Committee Assignments, 1948-1966
    - Conant, James B., correspondence, 1949-1952
    - Divinity School, 1952-1953
    - Duties of the Board, 1950
    - Elections to the Board, 1950-1955
    - Elections, Harvard Alumni Association, 1949-1954
    - Furry, Kamia, Markham controversy, 1953-1955
    - Harvard Club of Boston, 1949-1954
    - Honorary degrees, 1950-1955
    - Mathematics Visiting Committee, 1951
    - Meetings, 1949-1955, (3 folders)
    - 1949-1955, (5 folders) (Box 123)
    - Memoranda, 1950-1955
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1951-1955
    - Miscellany, 1953-1954 (Box 124)
    - Oppenheimer appointment to Board, 1948-1955
    - Oppenheimer appointment to committees, 1949-1955
    - Philosophy Department appointments, 1951-1952
    - Philosophy Visiting Committee, 1948-1966, (6 folders)
    - Physics and philosophy, 1950-1955 (Box 125)
    - Physics Department appointment, 1949-1954
    - Physics Visiting Committee, 1949-1955, (6 folders)
    - Pusey, Nathan (Box 126)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1956
      - Election as president, 1953-1954
    - Reports to the Board, 1950
    - Society of Fellows, 1950-1966
    - Summer School, 1951-1952
    - Visiting committees
      - Functions of, 1945-1954
      - Reports, 1947-1956
  - Harvard Foundation for Advanced Study, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 127)
    - Correspondence
      - Alumni, 1949-1953
      - Cambridge, Mass., office, 1949-1951
      - Crawford, Alfred, 1949
      - Huggins, Gordon, 1951-1953
      - McLaughlin, Donald, 1949-1950
      - New York office, 1949-1950
      - Pirnie, Malcolm, 1950-1951
    - Local chairmen, 1949-1950, (6 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953
    - Reports, 1949, (2 folders)
    - Special gifts committee, 1952
    - State chairmen, 1949-1950, undated, (3 folders)
  - Harvard University, classes of 1922 and 1926, 1950-1962, (5 folders) (Box 128)
  - Harvard University Ad Hoc Committee, Physics Department appointment, 1955-1956
  - Harvard University Observatory, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Boyden Station recommendation, 1953
    - Correspondence
      - Buck, Paul, 1952-1953
      - Conant, James B., 1952-1953
      - Miscellaneous, 1952-1953
      - Shapley, H., 1951-1952
    - Directorship, 1953-1957, (5 folders)
    - Reports to corporation, 1952
    - Survey Committee, 1952-1956, (4 folders)
    - Travel to meetings, 1950-1952
  - Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel (Box 129)
    - Board of Governors
      - Meeting arrangements, 1950-1966
      - Memoranda, 1950-1967
      - Oppenheimer appointment, 1950
      - Oppenheimer election as honorary governor, 1961
      - Reports, 1958
      - Resolutions, 1950-1956
    - Brodetsky, S.
      - Correspondence, 1950
      - Resignation, 1951
    - Einstein, Albert, correspondence, 1950-1954
  - Hebrew University, American Friends of the
    - Academic Advisory Council, 1952-1966
    - American and Canadian Board of Governors, 1951-1964
    - Blockade of road to Jerusalem, Israel, 1949
    - Board of Directors
      - Meeting arrangements, 1950-1964
      - Memoranda, 1951-1961
      - Oppenheimer appointment, 1950-1966
    - Board of Governors (Box 130)
      - Memorandum, 1951-1958
      - Minutes, 1950-1955
    - Bylaws, Undated
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1950-1966
      - Salpeter, High, 1949-1950
    - Dinner for Oppenheimer, 1960-1961
    - Executive Board, 1950-1954
    - Executive officer, 1951
    - Joint meeting of boards, 1950
    - Receptions, dinners, 1950-1964
  - Hugh Cabot Memorial Fund See Container 117, Cabot (Hugh) Memorial Fund
  - Institut des Hautes Etudes Scientifiques
    - Brochures, 1960
    - Clippings, 1958-1962
    - Committees (Box 131)
      - American, 1963-1967
      - Scientific, 1959-1961
    - Correspondence
      - Bauer, E., 1959
      - General, 1961-1964, (2 folders)
      - Grandpierre, André, 1963-1964
      - Lévy, Maurice, and Louis Michel, 1959-1961
      - Motchane, Léon, 1958-1966, (2 folders)
    - Oppenheimer visits to Paris, France, 1959-1965
    - Reports, statutes, 1959-1962
  - Institute for Experimental Medicine, 1957-1959 (Box 132)
  - Institute on Man and Science, 1965-1966
  - International Atomic Energy Agency Center for Theoretical Physics, 1963-1967, (5 folders)
  - International Conference on Economic Sanctions Against South Africa, 1963-1964
  - International Rescue Committee, 1950-1951, (2 folders) (Box 133)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, New York, N. Y., 1965-1966
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce, Tulsa, Okla., 1952
  - Kusaka Memorial Fellowship, 1948-1954
  - Lone Ranger National Council of Honor, 1949
  - Longmans, Green and Co., 1947-1948
  - Lord and Taylor Award, 1951-1958
  - Mark Twain Journal, 1955
  - Maryland, University of, College Park, Md., 1954-1966
  - Miami, University of, Coral Gables, Fla., 1965-1966
  - Minerva, 1967
  - Miss Fine's School, Princeton, N.J., 1948-1950, (2 folders)
  - Nassau Club, Princeton, N.J., 1948-1956 (Box 134)
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - Alaskan Science Conference, 1950
    - Atomic Energy Commission fellowship program, 1949-1950, (2 folders)
    - Business Sessions, 1947-1963
    - Civil Liberties Committee, 1948-1949
    - Committee on Scientific Conferences, 1951 (Box 135)
    - Council, 1946-1964, (7 folders)
    - Fellow nominations, 1949-1958, (2 folders)
    - Fellow nominations, 1949-1960, (1 folder) (Box 136)
    - Foreign associates, nomination of, 1949-1953
    - General correspondence, 1943-1966, (2 folders)
    - Marcellus Hartley Fund Committee, 1949-1952
    - Meetings, 1950-1951, (1 folder)
    - Meetings, 1950-1951, (2 folders) (Box 137)
    - National Science Foundation, 1947-1960
    - National Science Fund, 1948-1951
    - National Security Resources Board, 1950
    - Office of Ordnance Research, 1951
    - Organization, 1947-1966
    - Physics section, 1947-1963, undated, (5 folders)
    - President, 1950 (Box 138)
    - Press releases, Undated
    - Proceedings, 1947-1959
    - Research Board, 1945
    - Richards, A., correspondence, 1948-1950
    - Senate committee hearings, 1951
  - National Arts Foundation Public Advisory Committee, 1955
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1964-1965, (3 folders)
  - National Book Committee
    - General correspondence, 1955-1965
    - Minutes, 1954-1964
    - Oppenheimer appointment, 1954
  - National Civil Defense Committee, AMVETS, 1950-1951
  - National Committee on Atomic Information, 1946-1947
  - National Committee on Tithing in Investment, 1964-1966 (Box 139)
  - National Mental Health Foundation, 1946-1950
  - National Policy Committee, 1946-1947
  - National Research Council
    - Division of Scientific Personnel, 1952
    - Executive Board, 1950
    - Executive Committee, 1950-1955
    - Memoranda, 1948-1955
    - Reports to the council, 1948
    - Science policy advisory group, 1951
  - National Research Council and Social Science Research Council Joint Fellowship Board (Box 140)
    - Announcements, Undated
    - Applications, 1948-1951, (3 folders)
    - Appointments 1948-1949, (2 folders)
    - Arrangements for meetings, 1947-1948
    - Coale, Ansley, application, 1949
    - Fellowship program, 1952
    - Friedberg, Felix, application, 1949
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1948
    - Oppenheimer membership, 1947-1949 (Box 141)
    - Spitzer, Ralph, application, 1948-1950
  - National Testimonial Committee for Ambassador Abba Eban, 1959
  - New School for Social Research, New York, N.Y., 1958
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1948-1950
  - New York Bar Association
    - Committee on Atomic Energy, 1948-1955, (4 folders)
    - General, 1948-1953
  - New York Mineralogical Club, New York, N.Y., 1949-1963 (Box 142)
  - New York Philosophy Club, New York, N.Y., 1955-1967
  - New York University, New York, N.Y.
    - Bellevue Medical Center, 1957
    - Hall of Fame, 1949-1965, (3 folders)
    - Institute for Mathematics and Mechanics, 1948-1949
  - Niebuhr (Reinhold) Professorship Fund, 1960
  - Organization for Economic Co-operation, 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 143)
  - Pennsylvania, University of, Philadelphia, Pa., 1953
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1950
  - Philip M. Stern Family Fund See Container 145, Stern (Philip M.) Family Fund
  - Planned Parenthood, 1966
  - Princeton Community Chest, 1951-1954
  - Princeton Freedom Train Committee, 1948
  - Princeton Hospital Building Fund, 1949
  - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J.
    - Department of Electrical Engineering, 1954
    - Program on Science in Human Affairs, 1965
  - Pugwash Continuing Committee, 1947-1961
  - Reinhold Niebuhr Professorship Fund See Container 142, Niebuhr (Reinhold) Professorship Fund
  - Robert Porter Patterson Memorial Committee, 1952-1954
  - Rochester Conference Advisory Committee, 1956 (Box 144)
  - Rocky Mountain Empire Club 1955-1962
  - Romain Rolland 100th anniversary, 1966
  - Roosevelt (Eleanor) Memorial Foundation, 1963
  - Royal Society, London, England, 1951-1964
  - The Sciences, 1947
  - Seven Springs Farm Advisory Committee See Container 66, Seven Springs Farm
  - Social Science Research Council
    - Board of Directors, 1947-1949, (5 folders)
    - Committee on Faculty Research Grants, 1951-1952, (2 folders) (Box 145)
    - Election poll, 1948-1949
    - Fellowship announcements, 1948-1951
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1948-1951
  - Société Française de Physique, 1955-1959
  - Society for the Family of Man, 1965
  - Solvay Institute, Scientific Council, 1950-1962
  - Stern (Philip M.) Family Fund, 1963-1965
  - Tamiment Institute and Library, New York, N.Y., 1956-1959
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1957
  - Technion, 1948-1967, (2 folders)
  - Teilhard de Chardin Committee, 1960-1963
  - Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel, 1966
  - Twentieth Century Fund (Box 146)
    - Antitrust Policies Committee, 1951-1958, (3 folders)
    - Armaments, 1958-1961, (2 folders)
    - Berle, Adolf A., 1952-1962
    - Board of Trustees
      - Agenda, 1950-1965
      - Arrangements for meetings, 1951-1966
      - Ballot, 1950-1961
      - Documents for meetings, 1950-1960 (Box 147)
      - Memoranda, 1950-1967, (3 folders)
      - Minutes, 1950-1966, (3 folders)
      - Staff Reports, 1956 (Box 148)
    - Civil-Military Relations Committee, 1952-1954, (6 folders)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1962-1965
    - Congressional investigation of foundations, 1953-1957
    - Correspondence
      - Clark, Evans, 1950-1953
      - Dewhurst, J. R., 1953-1955
      - General, 1950-1966
      - Heckscher, August, 1957-1966, (2 folders) (Box 149)
      - Moore, Ben T., 1957-1958
      - Re Gordon A. Craig, Edward W. Fox, and Henry S. Hughes, 1951-1953
    - Cox Committee, 1951-1953
    - Executive Committee, 1951-1965, (2 folders)
    - Extremist propaganda study, 1953
    - Future prospects, 1954
    - General information, 1950-1966, (3 folders)
    - Mail votes, 1950-1960 (Box 150)
    - Meetings in Princeton, N.J., 1951-1952, 1963, (2 folders)
    - National Planning Association, 1950
    - Oppenheimer election to board, 1950-1966
    - “The People Act”, 1950-1951
    - Projects Committee, 1963
    - Proposals for political research, 1952
    - Prospective conferences, 1962-1963
    - Publications, lists of, 1949-1952
    - Reece Committee, 1953-1955
    - Research Projects Committee, 1950-1966, (3 folders); (5 folders) (Box 151)
  - UNESCO
    - Asian and Western cultural values, 1956
    - Citizen consultations plan, 1953-1954
    - Heindel, R. H., correspondence, 1952-1954
    - Invitations, 1948-1954
    - Law program, 1947
    - McCollough, M., 1952-1954 (Box 152)
    - Membership roster, 1952
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1954
    - National meetings, 1951-1953
    - National Research Council, 1952
    - Oppenheimer appointment as a member, 1947-1956
    - Program Committee, 1953-1954
    - Taylor, John W., memorandum, 1953
  - United Negro College Fund, 1960
  - United States Committee for United Nations Day, 1953-1954
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War Conference, 1963
  - Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovoth, Israel
    - American Committee, 1953-1967, (2 folders)
    - Board of Directors, 1958-1965
    - General correspondence, 1960-1966
    - Graduate School, 1964-1965
    - Kennedy fellowships, 1964-1966
    - Miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 153)
    - Notices, agenda, 1949-1964, (2 folders)
  - Weizmann (Chaim) World Memorial Committee, 1954
  - Wellesley Class of '56 1955-1956
  - World Academy of Art and Science, 1961-1965
  - World Perspectives, 1953-1966
  - Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association, 1957
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1945-1967 (Box 154-170)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, unpublished manuscripts received, and clippings, chiefly from autograph seekers or admirers.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person.
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1948-1966, (2 folders) (Box 154)
  - Aakula, Mrs. Tyne, 1955-1959
  - Advice requests, 1955
  - Aginsky, Burt W., 1957
  - Anonymous, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
  - A. T. G. (anonymous), 1961
  - Autograph requests, 1944-1966, (2 folders)
  - “B” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (6 folders) (Box 155)
  - Becroft, William, 1958-1959
  - Berko, Paul M., 1949-1950
  - Browne, Kenneth H., 1947-1956
  - Bullock, William E., 1963 (Box 156)
  - Burrow, Trigant, 1948-1950
  - “C” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (7 folders)
  - Chused, Lillian L., 1955-1958 (Box 157)
  - Cooper, Goldie, 1954-1955
  - Copeland, Arnold, 1956-1957
  - Corbett, Harriet, 1955
  - Cornillon, Jacques, 1963
  - Corrêa Netto, Orozimbo, 1948
  - "D" 1945-1967, (4 folders)
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
  - Esparza, Augusto, 1954-1966 (Box 158)
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (3 folders)
  - Flora, I. F., 1948-1964
  - Franck, Theodora, 1948
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (5 folders)
  - Gitelson, M. Leo, 1955 (Box 159)
  - Grossman, William, 1948-1949
  - “H” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (8 folders)
  - Hankey, Roland, 1949-1950 (Box 160)
  - Hawkins, Merrill, 1963
  - Herrod, B., 1946-1955
  - Hiller, Donald, 1960-1961
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1955-1965
  - "J" miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (2 folders)
  - J. S. D. (anonymous), 1957-1963
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1946-1966, ( 4 folders)
  - Kasper, Charles, 1953-1954 (Box 161)
  - Kemp, Robert, 1950-1952
  - Kerns, Calvin E., 1956-1958
  - Kinney, Wayne, 1962-1964
  - Kohn, David, 1955-1956
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (6 folders)
  - Lanier, E. A., 1955-1963 (Box 162)
  - Lebau, G. I., 1954-1967
  - Levine, Louis P., and Louis H. Levinson, 1948-1961
  - Lin, Frederick, 1956-1964
  - “M” miscellaneous
    - Ma-Me 1946-1967, (6 folders)
    - Mi-My, 1945-1967, (3 folders) (Box 163)
  - MacKellow, Sheila, 1955-1958
  - Malloy, Robert J., 1963
  - Marsh, Olive, 1952-1955
  - McCartney, Helen Barry, 1955-1957
  - McLellan, Martha F., 1963
  - Millar, W. N., 1960
  - Milliron, Paul J., 1957-1958
  - Mundlak, Max, 1950
  - Muses, Charles A., 1949-1955
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (3 folders) (Box 164)
  - Nikulins, Teopont E., 1949
  - Nyden, Shirley, 1954
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1948-1966
  - “P” miscellaneous
    - Pa-Pe, 1946-1967, (2 folders)
    - Ph-Pu, 1946-1967, (3 folders) (Box 165)
  - Page, Albert E., 1959-1962
  - Pausa, George J., 1949-1952
  - Pennebaker, Gregory, 1947-1963
  - Photograph requests, 1953-1967
  - Punch, Henry, 1955-1958
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1950, 1964
  - “R” miscellaneous
    - Ra-Re, 1946-1966, (3 folders)
    - Rh-Ry, 1945-1966, (3 folders) (Box 166)
  - Randall, Florence, Undated
  - Reali, Domenic, 1960
  - Rector, Robert Chapin, 1961-1964
  - Reese, C. Robert, 1955-1965
  - Requests for information, 1942-1947
  - Rice, William J., 1962-1964
  - Roberts, Alphaeus J., 1958-1963
  - Root, John C., Undated
  - Rosamond, Robert, 1949
  - Rusincky, E., 1953-1955
  - “S” miscellaneous, 1945-1967, (9 folders) (Box 167)
  - Safer, Josephine, 1949-1957 (Box 168)
  - Salin, Victoria, 1956
  - Scheiern, Milton R., 1962-1964
  - Silver, Henry, 1949-1950
  - Smedley, Frederic C., 1949-1950
  - Solounias, George, 1949-1964
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1946-1967, (3 folders)
  - Tabolski, E., 1964 (Box 169)
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1956-1965
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1950-1967
  - “W” miscellaneous
    - Wa-Wh, 1946-1966, (2 folders)
    - Wi-Wu, 1946-1967, (2 folders) (Box 170)
  - Webster, Jack M., 1948-1961
  - Weiss, Fred U., 1948-1955
  - Wiederhold, Albert G., 1963-1964
  - "Y" miscellaneous, 1949-1966
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1949-1966
- Government File, 1942-1954 (Box 171-196)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, bulletins, minutes, notices, travel vouchers, receipts for classified documents, and inventories relating to projects or agencies.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of project or agency.
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1948-1952 (Box 171)
  - Air defense, 1952-1953
  - Allied foreign policy, 1953
  - American District Telegraph Co., 1948-1953
  - American Society for Engineering Education, Committee on Atomic Energy, 1951
  - Armed Forces courier service, 1951-1953
  - Armed Forces Special Weapons Project, 1947-1951
  - Army Research Advisory Panel, 1947-1948
  - Associated Universities, Inc., 1951
  - Atom bomb, films, 1945-1947
  - Atomic energy, control of, 1945-1946, (2 folders)
  - Atomic Energy Commission
    - Ad hoc committee, 1949-1951
    - Automobile, loan of, 1947-1948
    - Board of Consultants, 1947-1949
    - Board of Review, 1947-1954
    - Cancer research, 1948 (Box 172)
    - Certificates of reproduction, 1950
    - Correspondence, 1946-1947, (2 folders)
    - Declassification, 1945-1951, (4 folders)
    - Fellowship program, 1948-1952, (2 folders) (Box 173)
    - General Advisory Committee See Containers 175 and 176, Atomic Energy Commission General Advisory Commission
    - Hydrogen bomb, 1950-1953, (2 folders)
    - Industrial Advisory Group, 1948
    - Information control policy, 1950
    - Instructions bulletins, 1950-1952
    - Inventories of documents, 1942-1955 (Box 174)
    - Miscellaneous bulletins, 1947-1955, (2 folders)
    - New York operations, 1949-1951
    - Organization charts, 1948-1953, (2 folders)
    - Press conferences, 1949-1952
    - Reactor Development Division, 1946-1947 (Box 175)
    - Research Division, 1950-1951
    - Security procedures, 1952-1954
    - Semiannual reports to Congress, 1949-1952
    - Thermonuclear Problems Conference, 1951
    - Travel, 1947-1953, (2 folders)
  - Atomic Energy Commission General Advisory Committee
    - Abstracting of papers, 1950-1951
    - Appointments, 1947-1952
    - Atomic power, 1948
    - Budget, 1950-1951
    - Correction notices, 1949-1952
    - Defense Department representatives, 1949 (Box 176)
    - Distribution of papers, 1947-1950
    - Establishment and function, 1948
    - Fellowship program, 1949
    - Information, 1946-1952
    - Mailing addresses, 1949-1951
    - Meeting arrangements, 1947-1952
    - Office space, 1948-1952
    - Oppenheimer to members, 1948-1950
    - Personnel policy, 1947